# **Geoffrey Maddock**

# Summary

I write code to make people's lives easier and more exciting.

I'm a seasoned programmer with over ten years of experience in web application development, working extensively, but not exclusively, with PHP, the Symfony Framework, Javascript, MySQL, Oracle, Unix and Windows based systems, CSS, Photoshop and standard modern tools employed by agile software developers. I work exceptionally well on my own or as part of a team and am skilled at transforming software requirements, from a laymen's request, into discrete milestones that can be refined and implemented into an effective and complete software solution.

Outside of my professional silo, I have experience running a small music business, event curation and planning as well as extensive audio engineering and DJ experience.

# **Work experience**

2005-Present

Expedient

Pittsburgh, PA

## Software Developer

- Design and develop web application software for a network, datacenter and managed-services company with a national profile.
- I have been the lead developer on a number of mission critical applications used by our Operations, Sales, Delivery and Support Teams.
- Work with stakeholders to create clear, custom code solutions using PHP, Symfony, Javascript, MySQL, Oracle DB and any other applicable tools in our stack.
- Won both solo and team based awards (Expys) in recognition for exceptional projects that helped support our organization.

2003-2005

Expedient

Pittsburgh, PA

#### **Network Operations Analyst**

- Handled escalated support requests for a major regional ISP and Datacenter.
- Designed a version of the company intranet website.

1999 - 2003

Stargate Industries

Pittsburgh, PA

#### **Corporate Technical Support Representative**

- Troubleshoot corporate and residential end-user problems in a call center environment, including problems with dialup, ISDN, DSL, T1 connectivity, email clients, websites and related issues.
- Training of new call-center employees in troubleshooting and company procedures.
- Performed shift-leader duties, including assisting other techs, answering email problems, and handling escalated cases

2001 - Present

WRECKED Distribution

Pittsburgh, PA

# **Owner and Operator**

- Owner and sole-proprietor of WRECKED part-time mail-order business
- Designed, coded, and maintain website, including a user system, shopping cart, and inventory control. Written from the ground up using PHP and MySQL.
   Designed and implemented the database using MySQL.
- Involved in all aspects of acquiring and distribution of experimental electronic music, from receiving purchases, to packing orders, coding, business and design issues.

1997 - 1999

Falk Computer and Media Center

Pittsburgh, PA

#### **Help Desk Assistant**

 Assist patrons in using a variety of software packages, including Microsoft Office, Photoshop, Medical Databases, on both Mac and Windows platforms.

#### **Education**

1995 - 1999

University of Pittsburgh

Pittsburgh, PA

### **Graduate with a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science**

 Applicable coursework: Database Management Systems, Data Structures and Algorithms, Programming Languages, Operating Systems, Artificial Intelligence

# **Computer skills**

Programming/Scripting: PHP, Javascript, Perl, Bash, Java, C++, HTML. MySQL and Oracle. I also have a strong foundation in underlying programming concepts. Operating Systems: Unix-based, Windows, Mac OS, Android.

Software and Tools: VI, Git + GitHub, Chrome Devtools, Sublime Text, Putty, WinSCP, cURL, Microsoft Office, Portal, Adobe Photoshop, Sound Forge.

Web/Design: Highly experienced with MVC and similar pattern based development, especially with the LAMP stack, and with Symfony 1.4 in specific, and Laravel 5.x to a lesser degree. Some experience with server side Javascript using Node, Express and Sails JS. Comfortable with front-end design using CSS, as well as graphic design for the web and print media.

Networking/Internet: Highly experienced in troubleshooting problems with Dial-Up Networking, ISDN, xDSL, Modems, Web Browsers, Email Clients, Web Sites and related issues. Understanding of TCP/IP, DNS, POP3 and other protocols.

# Other Experience

- Designed and implemented an event repo site for both one off and recurring events using Laravel framework and a MySQL backend. (http://events.cutupsmethod.com)
- Designed and coded site for Wrecked Distribution (<a href="http://wrecked-distro.com">http://wrecked-distro.com</a>), including the back-end database, user system, inventory system, administration tools, discussion forum and site layout.
- Built and maintained a Wordpress site with e-commerce integration for Lazercrunk (http://lazercrunk.com)
- Designed website for University of Pittsburgh Women's Studies department:
  Feminist Resources for Teens in Southwestern PA
- Consulted on design and implementation of the website <a href="http://girls-night-in.com">http://girls-night-in.com</a>, including installation and customization of OSCommerce and additional modules.
- Design of promotional flyers for local concerts and club nights.

#### References

Furnished on request.